# **Mukesh Prajapati**

+91 9901821625 mukeshsprajapati210@gmail.com DOB: 02-10-1994

An enthusiastic and self-motivated Software developer with an experience of 3+ years specializing in developing and testing large scale systems with strong background of object-oriented programming. Capable of working in a team or working individually following Agile methodology. I am continually seeking new challenge and desire to expand my knowledge and experience.

### **Experience**

#### **Infosys Ltd**

**08/2017 to Present** 

### COTD(Central Ordering Tool Demand) - Full Stack developer 06/2019 to Present

- Deals with loading 26 weeks forecast for all stores.
  Forecast filtering, aggregations. Forecast Validation & Adjustment.
- Started as UI developer using ReactJS and Javascript.
- Developed graphs using React-Highchart.
- Developed pages for fetching data from backend and showing them in table using React-data-grid.
- Later on, started with backend development too using Scala, Akka, Akka Streams, Cassandra and Solr.
- Developed an Akka Streams flow for fetching data from Cassandra and solr. Processing them and committing them back to db.
- Developing API using Akka Http.
- Helping end user with queries in application.
- Working in Agile methodology.

## MovIE(Movement and Inventory Engine) - Backend developer 03/2018 to 05/2019

- Providing Stock information of articles from all possible internal and external locations.
- Self-learnt Scala, Akka, Cassandra, Kafka and Streaming.
- Worked on various API by processing user input and providing them appropriate data from Cassandra.
- Developed streaming service to fetch data from Kafka node and process it after windowing. Saving data to db.
- Worked on recording metrics in Datadog.
- Learnt to use Kibana.
- Worked in Agile methodology.

### **Skill Highlights**

- Scala
- Akka
- Akka Streams
- Kafka
- Kafka Streams
- Javascript
- ReactJS
- Cassandra
- Solr
- Java
- Python
- Kibana
- Datadog
- React-highchart
- React-data-grid
- Webpack

#### **Education**

B. TECH(ICT): DAIICT - 2017

#### **Hobbies**

 Helping developers on Stackoverflow.

### **Social Profiles**

• https://stackoverflow.com/us ers/6863865/mukesh210